<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MintMentor</string>
    <string name="app_title">Mint Mentor</string>

    <string name="clear_database">Clear Lesson Database</string>


    <!-- Labels for bottom navigation -->
    <string name="home_label">Home</string>
    <string name="learn_label">Learn</string>
    <string name="about_label">About</string>
    <string name="account_label">Account</string>

    <string name="about_title">Welcome to Mint Mentor!</string>
    <string name="about_p1">This app provides the opportunity to learn about stocks and investing, in order to ensure a better financial future.</string>
    <string name="about_p2">There are several sections to learn about investing throughout the app, covering in detail all necessary information to begin or enhance your investing experience.</string>
    <string name="about_p3">The information in this app will take you through lessons on investing, risk management, building a successful portfolio, improving your financial literacy, and more</string>
    <string name="about_p4">At the end of each lesson, you will see a quiz on each lesson to help you comprehend the material best.</string>
    <string name="about_p5">We hope you enjoy!</string>
    <string name="about_p6">Grant Reddick and Ronak Ailawadi, creators</string>


    <string name="account_title">Account</string>
    <string name="learn_title">Learn</string>

    <string name="start_learning">Start Learning</string>

    <string name="learn_investing">Learn about investing here!</string>
    <string name="logo_description">Investment App Logo</string>

    <string name="complete">Take Quiz</string>
    <string name="return_to_lessons">Return to Lessons</string>

    <string name="please_select_answer">Please Select an Answer</string>

    <string name="next_question">Next Question</string>


    <string name="continue_learning">Continue Learning</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_quiz">Investment Basics Quiz</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_quiz">Financial Goals Quiz</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_quiz">Investment Securities Quiz</string>
    <string name="risk_return_quiz">Risk &amp; Return Quiz</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_quiz">Portfolio Construction Quiz</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_quiz">Investment Strategies Quiz</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_quiz">Tax Considerations Quiz</string>

    <!-- Lesson Buttons -->
    <string name="investment_basics_learn">Lesson 1: Investment Basics</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_learn">Lesson 2: Setting Financial Goals</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_learn">Lesson 3: Investment Securities</string>
    <string name="risk_return_learn">Lesson 4: Risk &amp; Return</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_learn">Lesson 5: Portfolio Construction</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_learn">Lesson 6: Investment Strategies, Research, &amp; Analysis</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_learn">Lesson 7: Tax Considerations</string>

    <string name="extra_info">Extra Info</string>
    <string name="investing_platforms_learn">Investing Platforms</string>
    <string name="resources_tools_learn">Resources &amp; Tools</string>


    <!-- Investment Basics -->
    <string name="investment_basics">Investment Basics</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_p1">So what exactly is “Investing”?</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_p2">You may have heard some people talking about it, and may have seen charts like this one:</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_p3">While investing may seem like a foreign concept, you too, can learn and ensure a better financial future.</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_p4">The dictionary definition is that “Investing is the strategic act of allocating your resources, usually money, with the goal of achieving financial growth and generating returns over time. It involves making deliberate choices about where to place your funds in various financial instruments and assets, aiming to increase their value or receive income in the future.”</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_p5">Confusing, right? Well, in essence, you can buy an asset (something with monetary value) and based on its price changes, you could make or lose money.</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_p6">However, it’s also important to be cautious with your finances. Investments can take extensive research and time to become profitable. Some investors don’t have that patience, and end up making irrational decisions, leading to financial losses.</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_p7">At the core of investing is the desire to see your initial investment (called capital) in an asset grow over time. This happens as the value of the investment increases due to factors like market demand, economic conditions, and the overall success of the asset, which we’ll get into soon.</string>
    <string name="image_vector_stock">Source:Vector Stock</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_vocab_list">
    \u2022Stocks: Equity securities representing ownership in a company. Stockholders may receive dividends and have voting rights at shareholder meetings.\n\n
    \u2022Index: A benchmark or reference point used to measure the performance of a group of assets or the overall market. Examples include the S&amp;P 500 and the Dow Jones Industrial Average.\n\n
    \u2022Yield: The income generated by an investment, often expressed as a percentage of the investment\'s value. For bonds, yield is typically referred to as "yield to maturity."\n\n
    \u2022Capital Gains: The profit earned from the sale of an investment or asset at a price higher than its purchase price.\n\n
    \u2022Bull Market: A period of rising stock prices and overall optimism in the market, typically characterized by increased investor confidence.\n\n
    \u2022Bear Market: A period of declining stock prices and pessimism in the market, marked by investor anxiety and a negative outlook.\n\n
    \u2022Asset Allocation: The strategy of dividing an investment portfolio among different asset classes (such as stocks, bonds, and cash) to manage risk and achieve specific financial goals.\n\n
    \u2022Diversification: The practice of spreading investments across different assets or asset classes to reduce risk. Diversifying can help minimize the impact of poor performance in a single investment.\n\n
    \u2022Portfolio: A collection of investments, such as stocks, bonds, and mutual funds, held by an individual or entity. Portfolios are designed to achieve specific financial objectives.\n\n
    \u2022Risk Tolerance: An individuals or investor\'s ability and willingness to withstand fluctuations in the value of their investments. It influences the choice of assets and the level of risk in a portfolio.\n\n
    \u2022Return: The profit or loss on an investment, expressed as a percentage of the original investment. It reflects the gains or losses from price appreciation, dividends, or interest.\n\n
    \u2022Volatility: The degree of variation in the price of an asset over time. Highly volatile assets may experience significant price fluctuations, while low volatility assets tend to have steadier prices.\n\n
    \u2022Liquidity: The ease with which an asset can be bought or sold in the market without affecting its price significantly. Cash is the most liquid asset, while real estate is less liquid.\n\n
    \u2022Dividend: A portion of a company\'s earnings that is paid out to shareholders on a regular basis, usually in the form of cash or additional shares of stock.\n\n
    \u2022Market Capitalization: The total value of a publicly traded company\'s outstanding shares of stock, calculated by multiplying the stock\'s price by the number of shares.\n\n
    \u2022Asset Class: A category of investments with similar characteristics and risk-return profiles, such as stocks, bonds, real estate, or commodities.\n\n
    \u2022Ticker Symbol: A stock symbol or ticker is a unique series of letters assigned to a security for trading purposes. For example, you may see Microsoft listed as MSFT on the stock market.
    </string>
    <string name="investment_basics_vocabulary">Vocabulary</string>


    <string name="investment_basics_q1">A bear market generally means which of the following?</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_q1_a1">Higher stock prices</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q1_a2">Technology companies come out with new products</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q1_a3">The stock market</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q1_a4">The government places higher taxes on companies</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q1_a5">Decreased investor confidence</string>


    <string name="investment_basics_q2">Profit in the stock market is usually called</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_q2_a1">Net gains</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q2_a2">Net profit</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q2_a3">Capital gains</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q2_a4">Capital profit</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q2_a5">Profitable gains</string>


    <string name="investment_basics_q3">The stock abbreviation used in trading is most often called the</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_q3_a1">Stock symbol</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q3_a2">Stock abbreviation</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q3_a3">Ticker symbol</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q3_a4">Stock share</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q3_a5">Stock information</string>


    <string name="investment_basics_q4">The Dow Jones Industrial Average is an example of</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_q4_a1">The S&amp;P 500</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q4_a2">A stock index</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q4_a3">Average stock prices over 200 days</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q4_a4">Average stock prices over 50 days</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q4_a5">A portfolio</string>


    <string name="investment_basics_q5">A stock is an example of</string>

    <string name="investment_basics_q5_a1">A company</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q5_a2">An asset</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q5_a3">The Dow Jones Industrial Average</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q5_a4">Volatility</string>
    <string name="investment_basics_q5_a5">An Index</string>




    <!-- Setting Financial Goals -->
    <string name="financial_goals">Setting Financial Goals</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_p1">There are many steps to setting effective and reachable financial goals.</string>

    <string name="financial_goals_p2">First, begin by reflecting on your current financial situation, needs, and aspirations. Consider factors such as your income, expenses, debt, savings, and any significant life events (buying a house, funding education, retiring). This evaluation helps you understand your starting point and prioritize your goals.</string>

    <string name="financial_goals_p3">Then, identify your financial goals in specific terms. For instance, rather than a vague goal like "save for the future," set specific goals. Examples of these include “save $10,000 for an emergency fund within the next two years" or "accumulate $50,000 for a down payment on a house in five years." With those goals you just created, categorize your goals into short–term, medium–term, and long–term. Short–term goals might include building an emergency fund or paying off high–interest debt within the next year. Medium–term goals could involve saving for a vacation, a car, or a home down payment within 2–5 years. Long–term goals might include retirement savings, children\'s education, or financial independence over a longer period of time (5–10+ years).</string>

    <string name="financial_goals_p4">Next, rank your goals based on their importance and urgency. Prioritizing helps you allocate resources more effectively and focus on what matters most. Keep in mind that balancing various goals requires careful consideration of timelines and available funds. An important part is to ensure your goals are specific and measurable. Include details like the amount of money needed, the time frame in which you aim to achieve the goal, and any specific actions required. Measurable goals allow you to track your progress and stay motivated. And, while it\'s important to dream big, set goals that are achievable given your current financial circumstances. Unrealistic goals can lead to frustration and disappointment, so it’s important to consider factors like your income, expenses, and the potential for growth in your investments (which we’ll talk about in other sections)</string>

    <string name="financial_goals_p5">Then, assign a realistic time frame to each goal to create a sense of urgency and encourage consistent effort towards achieving the goal. Regularly track your progress toward your financial goals. If circumstances change, be flexible and adjust your goals accordingly. Life events, personal growth, and external factors can all influence your goals.</string>

    <string name="financial_goals_p6">We’ll start talking about how you can meet these financial goals by investing now, and talk about Investment Securities.</string>

    
    <string name="financial_goals_q1">The first step in the financial goal setting process is</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q1_a1">Brainstorm any potential goals</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q1_a2">Ensuring goals are realistic</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q1_a3">Evaluate your financial situation</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q1_a4">Thinking about which of your goals is realistic</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q1_a5">Tracking progress towards any potential goals</string>

    <string name="financial_goals_q2">What are the three main types of goals to think about?</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q2_a1">Short term, medium term, and long term</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q2_a2">Immediate future, short term, long term</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q2_a3">Immediate future, medium term, long term</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q2_a4">Medium term, long term, very long term</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q2_a5">Medium term (focus the most on), immediate future, long term</string>

    <string name="financial_goals_q3">Which of the following is an example of a good short-term goal?</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q3_a1">Save for the future within six months</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q3_a2">Accumulate $500 for savings within a year</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q3_a3">Make more money over the next two years</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q3_a4">Accumulate $20,000 for a down payment on a house within 5 years</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q3_a5">Save enough for a future child’s education</string>

    <string name="financial_goals_q4">Which of the following is important to include when setting a goal?</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q4_a1">A goal that you are likely not able to meet, but will try your hardest to meet</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q4_a2">A goal that you will likely be able to meet</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q4_a3">A very broad goal that can guide many different parts of your life</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q4_a4">Track progress once a year to ensure you are meeting the goal</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q4_a5">Maintain your original goals and try to meet them no matter what, even if some circumstances change</string>

    <string name="financial_goals_q5">Which of the following is NOT an important characteristic of a goal?</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q5_a1">The goal is measurable</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q5_a2">The goal is somewhat specific</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q5_a3">The goal is broad and allows you to complete multiple tasks within it</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q5_a4">The goal has a time frame</string>
    <string name="financial_goals_q5_a5">The goal is regularly tracked</string>


    <!-- Investment Securities -->

    <string name="investment_securities">Investment Securities</string>


    <string name="investment_securities_p1">While “Securities” may mean something else to you, in the investing world it is a category. An example of this is a stock.
    Other investment vehicles include bonds, mutual funds and ETFs, real estate, and commodities.
        Let’s dive into each of them in detail here:</string>

    <string name="stocks">Stocks</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_p2">Investing in stocks means purchasing ownership shares in a company. As the company grows and succeeds, the value of its stock can increase, leading to potential capital gains. Additionally, some stocks pay dividends, providing regular income to investors.
        When you buy a company\'s stock, you become a partial owner of that company. Your ownership is proportional to the number of shares you hold compared to the total number of shares outstanding. As a shareholder, you have the potential to benefit from the company\'s success through capital appreciation and dividends.</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_p3">One of the primary ways to earn from stocks is through capital appreciation. If the company\'s value and profitability increase over time, the value of its stock and the stock price may rise as well. Investors can then sell their shares at a higher price than what they originally paid, resulting in a capital gain, or profit.
    Some companies also distribute a portion of their earnings to shareholders in the form of dividends. Dividends are periodic payments that can provide investors with a consistent income stream. Not all stocks pay dividends, and companies decide whether to pay dividends based on their financial health and growth plans.
    Investing in stocks is often most effective when approached with a long-term perspective. While short-term market fluctuations are normal, holding onto quality stocks over time can potentially lead to significant returns, especially when the power of compounding comes into play. We’ll talk about strategy in a bit as well.</string>

    <string name="bonds">Bonds:</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_p4">Bonds are debt securities issued by governments or corporations. When you buy a bond, you\'re essentially lending money to the issuer in exchange for interest.</string>


    <string name="mutual_and_etfs">Mutual Funds and ETFs:</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_p5">These investment vehicles pool money from multiple investors to invest in a diversified portfolio of assets. They provide instant diversification and are managed by professionals. We’ll also talk about ETFs soon.
    Investing in real estate involves purchasing properties with the aim of generating rental income and capital appreciation. Real estate can offer both income and potential growth over time, especially if you purchase a property and rent it out while it appreciates in value.
    You can also invest in commodities, or physical goods like gold, oil, and agricultural products. Investing in commodities can act as a hedge against inflation, as the prices of commodities often rise.
        Commodity, real estate, and bond trading is more complicated than stocks and ETFs. So, for now, we’ll be focusing on stocks and ETFs.</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_p6">
        Let’s back it up a bit. The stock market is open from 9:30 am EST to 4:00 pm EST Monday through Friday (there are some holidays where it is closed, listed <a href='https://www.nyse.com/markets/hours-calendars'>here</a>). Some trading platforms allow you to purchase shares of stock (remember, these are partial ownership units, and what you buy when you “buy a stock”) pre-market, from 6:00 am EST to 9:30 am EST, and after-hours, from 4:00 pm EST to 8:00 pm EST. However, it’s important to remember that unless there is some big news for a company, the stock price will remain relatively unchanged premarket and after-hours, and the bulk of the trading will take place during the day (9:30am to 4:00pm).</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_p7">In addition, a stock\’s closing price is its price at 4:00pm of the trading day, while its opening price is at 9:30am of the day.</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_p8">There are many numbers to look at when viewing a stock, and they\’re important to know. Let\’s take a look at one stock in particular, Roku Inc (pictured above). The stock\’s price, or share price, is $76.26. So, to purchase one (1) share of the company, it costs $76.26.</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_p9">It shows <font fgcolor='#FF0000'>-1.54 (-1.98%)</font>, meaning that the share price for the company has decreased $1.54 during that particular day compared to the previous day’s close price of $77.80. The “Day’s Range” shows the lowest and highest that the share price has been that day, while the “52 Week Range” shows the same thing for the past year.
    The volume is how many shares of stock have been traded on a given day. On this day, for example, 4,941,058 shares have been traded, but usually that is around 8,557,148 shares traded per day.
    Now, let’s look at the graph. Let’s say a man, Jonathan, bought ten (10) shares of ROKU in March 2023 at a price of $57.00 per share. In April 2023, the price was around $53.00 per share, so at that point, Jonathan was losing $4.00 per share, or a total of $40.00 due to his ten shares. If Jonathan decided to sell the shares at that price, he would definitively lose the $40.00.</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_p10">However, if he kept the shares until August 2023, the price would be at $80.00, and he would be making $23.00 per share, or a total of $230.00. Again, if Jonathan does not sell the shares, the loss or gain is not definitive. If he wants to claim his gain of $230.00, he must sell the shares, and then he does not have to worry about the future price of the share.
        Bid, Ask, and the rest of the concepts will be discussed later.</string>


    <string name="investment_securities_q1">Which of the following is NOT a security in the investing world?</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q1_a1">Bonds</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q1_a2">Stocks</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q1_a3">Mutual Funds</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q1_a4">ETFs</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q1_a5">The government to prevent someone from committing stock fraud</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_q2">When is the stock market usually closed all day?</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q2_a1">On the weekends</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q2_a2">On Fridays</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q2_a3">On the weekends and on Fridays</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q2_a4">Election day</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q2_a5">Election day and the weekends</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_q3">The closing price of a stock is the price at, in EST,</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q3_a1">Midnight</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q3_a2">Noon</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q3_a3">8:00pm</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q3_a4">4:00pm</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q3_a5">9:30am</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_q4">The volume of a stock shows</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q4_a1">How many shares have been traded on a given day</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q4_a2">The area covered by the stock’s graph</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q4_a3">How much the stock costs</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q4_a4">The average price of the stock over the past year</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q4_a5">The average price of the stock over the past day</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_q5">If you buy ten shares of ROKU at $5.00, and it goes up to $10.00, how much did you make in capital gains (profit)?</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q5_a1">$5.00, because the difference between $10.00 and $5.00 is $5</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q5_a2">$50.00, because you made $5.00 on each of your ten shares</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q5_a3">- $50.00, because you bought the stock at a lower price than it currently is at</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q5_a4">- $5.00, because you bought the stock at a higher price than it is currently at</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q5_a5">$0.00, because you never sold the stock, so there are no capital gains</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_q6">True or False: The stock market is only open between 9:30am and 4:00pm EST Monday-Friday</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q6_a1">False, the stock market is not open on Fridays</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q6_a2">False, the stock market is open between 9:30am and 4:00pm PST, not EST</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q6_a3">False, some platforms allow people to trade pre-market and after-hours in addition to these times</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q6_a4">True, these are the only times that someone can trade during the year, but sometimes the stock market is closed for holidays</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q6_a5">True, the stock market is open each Monday-Friday of the year from 9:30am to 4:00pm EST</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_q7">The opening price of a stock is its price at, in EST,</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q7_a1">9:30 am, when regular trading begins</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q7_a2">6:00 am, when early trading begins</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q7_a3">4:00 pm, when after-hours trading begins</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q7_a4">8:00 pm, when after-hours trading begins</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q7_a5">12:00 am (midnight), when the day opens</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_q8">Debt securities issued by governments or corporations are called</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q8_a1">Mutual Funds</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q8_a2">Government Funding</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q8_a3">Bonds</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q8_a4">Stocks, but some are called ETFs</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q8_a5">Commodities</string>

    <string name="investment_securities_q9">Periodic payments that are distributed by companies as a portion of their earnings are called</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q9_a1">Loans</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q9_a2">Investor Gratitude</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q9_a3">Capital Gains</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q9_a4">Goodwill</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q9_a5">Dividends</string>


    <string name="investment_securities_q10">Examples of commodities include ALL except</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q10_a1">Stocks</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q10_a2">Gold</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q10_a3">Oil and Natural Resources</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q10_a4">Agriculture</string>
    <string name="investment_securities_q10_a5">Cows</string>







    <!-- Risk and Return -->
    <string name="risk_and_return">Risk &amp; Return</string>

    <string name="risk_return_p1">Analyzing risk and return is arguably one of the most important parts of the stock market. So, what is it? Well, when you purchase a share of stock, it has the possibility of increasing or decreasing in value, resulting in you either making or losing money. If the price is higher than you bought it at, you are making money, and losing money if the price is lower than what you bought it at.</string>

    <string name="risk_return_p2">The primary goal of investing in the stock market is to profit. However, greed and the desire for more money can contribute to irrational decisions seeking further profit. It’s important to invest in stable stocks. Some examples of these are the 30 companies on the Dow Jones Industrial Average.</string>

    <string name="risk_return_p3">In addition, occasionally, you may see “meme” stocks. Examples in the past have included AMC, GameStop, etc, and it’s important to stay away from these, as well as penny stocks (stocks that are around $5 per share). This is because they often bring high volatility, and can result in large losses.</string>

    <string name="risk_return_p4">As we see here, AMC Entertainment Holdings (Stock Ticker AMC) was around $20 in December of 2020. However, for no significant reason, it rose 2800%. Anyone who purchased shares for even $200 would be at a huge loss today. In addition, while some stocks should be held long-term, sometimes it’s also beneficial to take a profit. Take AMC again, for example. Owners of the stock at $20 per share could have sold at $500 per share, resulting in profit of $480 per share. However, if they did not sell it at that point and held onto it, they would be at a loss of $12.20 per share (as the share price is now $7.80). Remember, you do not make or lose any money until a stock is sold. As a general rule of thumb, I like to think that when a stock increases by 300%, it may be a good idea to sell the shares. Remember, you can always buy a stock again later.</string>

    <string name="risk_return_p5">During a recession (when the economy is not doing well), it may be a good idea to shift away from cyclical stocks - companies that make money from unnecessary spending and follow the pattern of the economy, like Disney, Travel Companies, and other more “luxury” companies, and move to non-cyclicals - essentials like Kroger and things needed no matter the state of the economy.</string>

    <string name="risk_return_p6">We’ll discuss stop loss orders soon as well, which can be a method of preventing losses and keeping profits. In order to mitigate risk and improve returns, it’s important to keep a diversified portfolio, and that’s what we’ll talk about next.</string>


    <string name="risk_return_q1">What is the Dow Jones Industrial Average?</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q1_a1">An index measuring the stock prices of 30 companies</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q1_a2">An average of all large companies’ stock prices in the United States</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q1_a3">An average of all large companies’ stock prices in the world</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q1_a4">The average number of shares bought and sold in the US over a day</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q1_a5">The average number of shares bought and sold in the World over a day</string>

    <string name="risk_return_q2">As a general rule of thumb, which of the following times should cause you to sell the stock most often?</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q2_a1">After the price increases by $10 per share</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q2_a2">After you make enough money to purchase something you would like</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q2_a3">After a company decides to create a new product</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q2_a4">After a share price increases by 300% or more over a short period of time</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q2_a5">After the prices increases by over $100 per share</string>

    <string name="risk_return_q3">During a recession, which of the following companies should you not invest in?</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q3_a1">Royal Caribbean Cruises</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q3_a2">Kroger</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q3_a3">CVS</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q3_a4">All companies based in China</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q3_a5">Any non-cyclical stock</string>

    <string name="risk_return_q4">Which of the following is an example of a cyclical stock?</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q4_a1">Campbell’s Soup</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q4_a2">McDonald\'s</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q4_a3">Amazon</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q4_a4">DTE Energy</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q4_a5">Eli Lilly</string>

    <string name="risk_return_q5">Which is the best reason to generally avoid “meme” stocks?</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q5_a1">You should not trust people on Reddit for investing advice</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q5_a2">There are only a few meme stocks that actually go up</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q5_a3">Meme stocks are often more volatile than typical stocks, which can result in larger losses</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q5_a4">Meme stocks are often too expensive to purchase</string>
    <string name="risk_return_q5_a5">Meme stocks increase in price too fast</string>



    <!-- Portfolio Construction -->
    <string name="portfolio_construction">Portfolio Construction</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_p1">A portfolio is a collection of financial assets, and in this case, stocks. We’ll discuss the three major indexes and how to “diversify” your portfolio. The three major indexes are the Standard and Poor (S&amp;P) 500, the Dow Jones Industrial Average, and the Nasdaq. These measure the performance of the stock market, and give a general idea of the overall state of stocks.</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_p2">The S&amp;P 500 is usually the best indicator of the state of the market, simply because it contains so many companies - the 500 largest public companies, across all sectors.</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_p3">The Dow Jones Industrial Average is made up of 30 stocks, and is generally what is referred to as “the market.” However, due to the Dow Jones’ small size, most investors look at the S&amp;P 500 to evaluate the overall market condition.</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_p4">The Nasdaq, or Nasdaq Composite, is composed primarily of technology companies - this includes companies like Apple, Microsoft, Tesla, Amazon, etc.</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_p5">While you cannot invest directly in these indexes, there are ETFs (exchange-traded funds) to invest in them. ETFs measure multiple companies in one “stock”, so they are often used to invest in an entire industry.</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_p6">Let’s take a look at the US Global Jets ETF (JETS). While you can invest in individual airline stocks, such as American Airlines, Delta Airlines, United Airlines, etc, this ETF provides a glimpse into the Airline Industry as a whole. As we can see, Delta, Southwest, United, American, and more airlines are represented, all in this one price. ETFs can sometimes be a safer bet than individual stocks. Say, for example, American Airlines has a problem with many of their planes, while other airlines do not. While investors in American Airlines may lose money if the stock price drops, investors in the JETS ETF may not lose as much money, since American Airlines only makes up about 10% of it.</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_p7">There are also Index-wide ETFs that track the Dow Jones, S&amp;P 500, and Nasdaq. For example, the ETF SPY tracks the S&amp;P 500 Index. It mirrors the price (at a 10x smaller scale) and is a solid investment option. Annually, it provides about a 5% return, so it is a very solid option to invest in.</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_p8">As we can see here, they mirror each other directly. The only difference is that one is able to purchase the SPY ETF, while someone is not able to purchase the actual S&amp;P 500. There is essentially no difference, however, as SPY simply tracks the S&amp;P 500.</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_p9">It’s important to build a portfolio of a wide variety of stocks and ETFs. In order to do so, let’s take a look at the S&amp;P 500 sectors, or categories of companies, with some examples. A full list of companies and sectors can be viewed <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_S%26P_500_companies'>here</a>.</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_p10">As a general rule of thumb, it is often best to diversify your portfolio across these sectors, and own shares of at least 3–5 companies in each sector listed above to begin, and the number should be generally similar across each sector. If you’re having trouble deciding which ones to purchase, that’s what we’ll look at next, with Investment Strategies, Research, and Analysis.</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_q1">JETS includes many companies, so it is an example of a(n)</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q1_a1">Stock</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q1_a2">Bond</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q1_a3">ETF</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q1_a4">Share</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q1_a5">Index</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_q2">SPY is an Index-wide ETF that mirrors the price of the S&amp;P 500 (at a 10x smaller interval). If SPY increases in price by 5%, what does this show about the change in price of the S&amp;P 500?</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q2_a1">The S&amp;P 500 has increased in price by 5%</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q2_a2">The S&amp;P 500 has decreased in price by 50%</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q2_a3">The S&amp;P 500 has increased in price by 50%</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q2_a4">The S&amp;P 500 has decreased in price by $50</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q2_a5">The S&amp;P 500 has increased in price by $50</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_q3">Which of the following is not a sector of the S&amp;P 500?</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q3_a1">Real Estate</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q3_a2">Energy</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q3_a3">Communication Services</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q3_a4">Cyclical/Luxury</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q3_a5">Materials</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_q4">Examples of companies in the Industrial Sector include all of the following EXCEPT</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q4_a1">American Airlines</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q4_a2">FedEx</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q4_a3">3M Company</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q4_a4">Exxon Mobil</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q4_a5">Caterpillar Inc</string>

    <string name="portfolio_construction_q5">Carnival Cruise Line (CCL) has several cruises that have mechanical issues, so the stock price falls by 10% in one day. However, your portfolio only decreases in value by 2% that day. Which of the following could explain this?</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q5_a1">Carnival Cruise Line increases in the next day</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q5_a2">You own shares of companies other than Carnival Cruise Line</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q5_a3">You own an ETF that includes Carnival Cruise Line</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q5_a4">You ignore the news of Carnival Cruise Line, so your shares are not impacted</string>
    <string name="portfolio_construction_q5_a5">Both b and c are possible</string>



    <!-- Investment Strategies -->
    <string name="investment_strategies">Investment Strategies, Research, and Analysis</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_p1">There are several metrics that are important to be looked at to determine market sentiment. One of these is called the Advance/Decline Index, pictured below:</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_p2">This graph shows the volume of shares being purchased vs sold - remember, when people buy shares, stock share prices rise, and vice versa when shares are sold. As you can see, the Nasdaq companies have been sold more often than the other three here, showing how the overall buyer sentiment of the Nasdaq was declining. This could be seen since the beginning of August, giving an advantage to traders who viewed this.</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_p3">Another graph which we will look at is the Arms Index.</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_p4">As you can see, the Arms Index value is 1.66 for the S&amp;P 500, 1.22 for the Dow Jones, and 0.6808 for the Nasdaq. Typically, a value under 1 signals a somewhat decent buying opportunity, while a value over 1 typically signals a somewhat decent selling opportunity. Remember, this is an important metric, but all of these metrics must be combined with each other to provide the most accurate feeling for the market. You can view both charts here.</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_p5">It’s also important to invest in both value and growth companies. Value companies are stocks that consumers need, and are not just based on a social trend. These often include dividends, or an extra bonus credited to you every quarter. As an example, let’s take a look at FedEx (FDX)</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_p6">As you can see, the “Forward Dividend &amp; Yield” is $4.82 per year. This means that if you own shares of the company, you will be credited an extra $4.82 each year ($1.20 per quarter). While this may not seem like much, over time, dividends add up and can be a major contributor to investments.</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_p7">In addition, the P/E Ratio is a great indicator of a company’s value. It measures the share price and compares it to the company’s earnings. Essentially, it indicates whether a company is undervalued, fairly valued, or overvalued. Typically, companies with a PE Ratio of around or under 15 are undervalued, around 30 are fairly valued, and around or above 50 are overvalued. As we can see, FedEx (FDX) has a PE Ratio of 16.19, meaning it may be a slightly undervalued company and that it may present a buying opportunity.</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_p8">Growth stocks can also prevent an investing opportunity. However, they are often more risky than “value” stocks, and often suffer during economic downturn. Examples of these include Technology stocks, and these often do not have dividends. An advantage, however, is that they can rise much faster than value stocks, though with more risk.</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_p9">It’s also important to pay attention to jobs report data, which can give an overall view of the economy and therefore consumer sentiment. The data is usually released monthly, on the morning of the first Friday. The CPI (measure of inflation) is also released monthly (between the first and second week of the month), and both can impact the stock market. Finally, pay attention to the decisions of the Federal Reserve. Usually, when they raise interest rates, investing decreases and the market drops (or often will drop at some point in the future). However, when they decrease interest rates, the opposite happens. These can help indicate the strength of the economy and stock market.</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_q1">An Arms Index value under 1 most directly represents</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q1_a1">A good buying opportunity</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q1_a2">A good selling opportunity</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q1_a3">A good opportunity to hold a stock where it is at</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q1_a4">A potential time of volatility</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q1_a5">A potential time of calmness in the stock market</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_q2">A dividend date for Company A is January 3rd, you own 10 shares, and the dividend is $4.00. How much will you be paid per share on July 3rd?</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q2_a1">$0.00, because the dividend date is on January 3rd</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q2_a2">$2.00, because July 3rd is halfway through the year</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q2_a3">$4.00, because the dividend is $4.00</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q2_a4">$1.00, because the ¼ of the dividend is distributed quarterly</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q2_a5">$8.00, because the dividend doubles every 6 months</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_q3">When the Federal Reserve increases interest rates, the stock prices in the stock market are most likely to</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q3_a1">Decrease, because less money will be borrowed and put into the stock market</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q3_a2">Decrease, because more money will be borrowed and put into the stock market</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q3_a3">Increase, because less money will be borrowed and put into the stock market</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q3_a4">Increase, because more money will be borrowed and put into the stock market</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q3_a5">Stock prices will likely not change</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_q4">You find a stock that has a P/E ratio of 20. In most cases, should you buy the stock?</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q4_a1">No, as the P/E ratio shows it may be slightly undervalued</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q4_a2">Yes, as the P/E ratio shows it may be slightly undervalued</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q4_a3">Yes, as the P/E ratio shows it may be slightly overvalued</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q4_a4">No, as the P/E ratio shows it may be slightly overvalued</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q4_a5">Possibly, but you should wait to see the future P/E ratio</string>

    <string name="investment_strategies_q5">You decide to invest in Alphabet Inc (GOOGL), a technology company. Which of the following is NOT true about the stock?</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q5_a1">The stock is likely a growth stock</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q5_a2">The stock is likely to suffer during economic downturn</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q5_a3">The stock is likely to have a dividend</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q5_a4">The stock is likely more risky than a typical value stock</string>
    <string name="investment_strategies_q5_a5">The stock is likely to be affected by rising interest rates by the federal reserve</string>



    <!-- Tax Considerations -->
    <string name="tax_considerations">Tax Considerations</string>

    <string name="source_carta">Source: Carta</string>
    <string name="source_investopedia">Source: Investopedia</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_p1">When investing, you do have to pay taxes on profits. However, the taxes only apply to stocks that have been sold (called realized gains or losses). So, if you own a stock, you do not have to pay taxes on it, but once you sell it, you do.</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_p2">Taxes are also different on short-term stocks vs long-term stocks. A short-term stock is one owned for less than one consecutive year, while a long-term stock is a stock owned and sold after more than one consecutive year. For example, if you bought a stock in January 2023, you would need to hold it until January 2024 for it to be considered long term. If you sold it before then, it would be considered short-term. This distinction is important; short term and long term stocks are taxed at different rates.</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_p3">Short-term stocks are taxed at your normal income tax bracket. As a reminder, here’s a table with the values:</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_p4">Long term capital gains are taxed at a lower rate than short term gains, with a maximum of 20% capital gains tax.</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_p5">However, it’s important to not let these tax statistics impact you in a negative way. This does not mean to hold a stock just to have your gains taxed at a lower rate - if you feel it is a good idea to sell the stock, you should do so. But, if you are very closely approaching the one year period, it may be a good idea to evaluate your situation with the stock and whether you would like to keep it for the lower tax rate.</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_p6">Finally, you can offset gains with $3,000 in losses each year. For example, if you make $10,000 in realized gains in one year, and have $3,000 in realized losses, you do not have to pay taxes on the $10,000, and instead only pay taxes on the $7,000, or your net gain. If you have more than $3,000 in losses, you can only offset $3,000 per year, but the remaining amount can go towards your taxes in future years.</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_p7">For example, if you have an income of $70,000, and you have $10,000 in realized losses, you will only be taxed on $67,000 that year, as up to $3,000 in losses can be deducted from taxable income each year. The remaining $7,000 in realized losses will carry over to the next year, $4,000 to the next year, and so forth.</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_q1">You purchase Oracle stock (ORCL) in December 2022 at a price of $99 per share. In February 2024, you sell ORCL at a loss, at $85 per share. If you are single and making $65,000 per year, your tax rate on ORCL is</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q1_a1">15%, because it is a long-term capital gain</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q1_a2">0%, because you did not sell the stock for a gain, so you don’t have to pay taxes</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q1_a3">20%, because it is a long-term capital gain</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q1_a4">22%, because it is a short-term capital gain</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q1_a5">37%, because you paid over $70 per share</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_q2">You purchase Amazon stock (AMZN) in January of 2023. In October 2023, you decide to sell AMZN. If you are single and making $70,000 a year, what is the tax rate you must pay on your gains?</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q2_a1">12%</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q2_a2">15%</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q2_a3">22%</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q2_a4">32%</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q2_a5">37%</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_q3">If you have an unrealized loss of $3,000, but a realized gain of $5,000, how much do you have to pay taxes on during that year?</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q3_a1">$2,000, because your $3,000 in losses can offset $3,000 of gains</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q3_a2">$8,000, because you have to pay taxes on gains and losses</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q3_a3">$0, because you do not have to pay taxes on either</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q3_a4">$5,000, because you cannot offset your realized gains with an unrealized loss</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q3_a5">$3,000, because you only pay taxes on unrealized gains and losses</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_q4">If you have a realized loss of $4,000, but a realized gain of $6,000, how much do you have to pay taxes on during that year?</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q4_a1">$0, because you only pay taxes on unrealized gains and losses</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q4_a2">$2,000, because your $4,000 in losses offsets $4,000 in gains</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q4_a3">$10,000, because you must pay taxes on realized gains and losses</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q4_a4">$3,000, because only $3,000 of realized gains can be offset by losses each year</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q4_a5">$6,000, because you only pay taxes on realized gains</string>

    <string name="tax_considerations_q5">What is considered true regarding a long-term vs short-term capital gain/realized gain?</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q5_a1">Long term stocks have been held for over a year, while short term stocks have not</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q5_a2">Long term stocks have been held for more than 5 years, while short term stocks have not</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q5_a3">Long term stocks have been held for over a month, while short term stocks are ‘day traded’ stocks</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q5_a4">Long term capital gains are taxed at a lower rate than short term capital gains</string>
    <string name="tax_considerations_q5_a5">Answers A and D are both true</string>



    <!-- Investing Platforms -->
    <string name="investing_platforms">Investing Platforms</string>

    <string name="robinhood">Robinhood</string>


    <string name="e_trade">E*TRADE</string>


    <string name="fidelity">Fidelity</string>


    <string name="td_ameritrade">TD Ameritrade\n(Charles Schwab)</string>


    <string name="m1_finance">M1 Finance</string>


    <string name="wealthfront">Wealthfront</string>


    <string name="merrill_lynch">Merrill Lynch</string>
    <string name="check_answer">Check Answer</string>
    <string name="finish_quiz">Finish Quiz</string>


</resources>